Animikh Aich Team Lead – Delhi

Phone: (+91) 96119-33016

Website: animikh.me

Email (work): animikh@wobot.ai

Email (personal): animikhaich@gmail.com

Linkedin: *linkedin.com/in/animikh-aich*

GitHub: *github.com/animikhaich*

Location: Delhi, India

Skills

Tensorflow PyTorch

OpenCV Numpy

Keras Python

Docker Scikit-Image

Initiation

Co-Founded "Team Technoids"

It is an Initiation to introduce the students of our college to the exciting world of Artificial Intelligence and Computer Vision through introductory workshops.

The responsibility of the same has been handed over to a selected few, and hence is currently being maintained by them.

Education

- 2015-2019 RNS Institute of Technology, Bangalore, IN
 BE, Electronics and Communication Engineering
- 2008-2015 Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan,
 Kolkata, IN
 Science PCMB

Experience

JUL 2020–Present Team Lead – Delhi | Wobot Intelligence

- Lead a team of 9 Developers at the Delhi Office, along with up to 5 Interns.
- **Developed** Proprietary **Multi Stream Inference Architectures** for both Intel CPUs and Nvidia GPUs using **OpenVINO Model Server** and **Tensorflow Serving**.
- Lead the development of the Product, which consisted of 5 Use-Cases based on up-to 8 Deep Learning Models running on an Intel CPU for Multiple Streams.
- Developed Face Mask Detection and Handwash Detection using Light-weight and
 Optimized Algorithms, which became a few of the key models used in the Product.
- Contributed to the development of **Wobot Toolkit** a Generalized Model Training and Dataset Management/Annotation toolkit used for fast prototyping internally.
- Developed Efficient Data and Model Training pipelines using Tensorflow that allowed faster and more optimized training, using Tf.Data, XLA, and Mixed Precision (FP16) Training, thus reducing Model Training time to ~1/5th.
- Conducted the technical round of interview for recruits.

JUN 2019–JUN 2020 Computer Vision Engineer | Wobot Intelligence

- Worked as a developer in the **R&D** and **Product Development** Team.
- Devised Synthetic Dataset Generation Algorithms which allowed to artificially generate data for Object Detection.
- **Developed** and **deployed** several algorithms for real-time object detection, tracking, and classification on **CCTV footage**.
- Worked on developing a novel person reidentification algorithm, which is used to re-identify a person and hence calculate his accurate wait-time even when the object of interest suffers from lengthy occlusions.
- Worked on IP creation by leading the development of an optimized person detector, fine-tuned for CCTV footage, as well as creating object detectors for other custom objects.
- Worked on the optimization and deployment of Deep Learning models at scale for both edge and cloud.
- Hands-on with Deep Learning Toolkits: Intel's OpenVINO Toolkit, Nvidia's Transfer Learning Toolkit (TLT), and Tensorflow Lite.
- Deployed several models on servers by integrating them with Flask and Tensorflow Serving APIs. Additionally, used Docker for containerized deployments.
- Conducted the technical round of interview for recruits.

JUL-AUG 2019 Freelance Technical Blogger | KnowledgeHut

FEB-JUL 2019 Freelance Technical Blogger | ZeoLearn

JAN-MAR 2019 Data Science Intern | KrishiHub (Letter)

JAN 2018 Artificial Intelligence Intern | <u>KnightsRoboCorp</u> (<u>Certificate</u>)

Publications (Google Scholar Link)

- "Encoding Web-based Data for Efficient Storage in Machine Learning Applications" | ICInPro-2019 | IEEE (Link)
- "Sentiment Analysis of Restaurant Reviews using Machine learning Techniques" | ICERECT-2018 | Springer (Link)
- "Analysis of Customer Opinion Using Machine Learning and NLP Techniques" | ICCS-2018 | Elsevier (<u>Link</u>)
- "Sales-forecasting of Retail Stores using Machine Learning Techniques" | CSITSS-2018 | IEEE (Link)

Projects - College / Personal

Facial Recognition Dashboard | (GitHub)

Highlights: Front-End Dashboard, Face Detector, Face Recognizer

Keywords: Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Python, MTCNN, VGG-Face, Flask, HTML, CSS

Automatic Helmetless Rider Detection using Deep Learning | Final Year Project | (YouTube)

Highlights: Helmet/No-Helmet Detection, License Plate Detection, and Custom OCR

Keywords: Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Python, Classification, Detection

Classification of Normal and AF ECG Signals using Convolutional Neural Networks | (GitHub)

Highlights: 1D-CNNs, 93.10% accuracy with 14.7M parameters *Keywords:* Tensorflow, Pandas, Python, Jupyter Notebook

Time-Lapse Creator Desktop App | (GitHub)

Highlights: Graphical User Interface (GUI), Video Reader, Video Writer, Developed for Real-World use-case

Keywords: Tkinter, OpenCV, Python

University Result Downloader Desktop App | RNSIT ECE | (YouTube) (GitHub)

Highlights: Web-Scraping, Graphical User Interface (GUI), Used by Dept. of ECE, RNSIT

Keywords: PyQT5, Pandas, Python, Requests, BeautifulSoup

Facial Recognition Based Door Lock/Unlock System | Project at "The Valley Bootcamp" | (GitHub)

Highlights: Arduino Uno, Facial Recognition System, Face Detector, USB Serial Interface for Python

Keywords: Face Recognition, OpenCV, Python, DLib, PySerial

Other Projects

- Invisible Cloak using OpenCV [APR 2019] (GitHub)
- Word-based **Sentiment Analysis** Model using **Naïve Bayes Classifier** [MAR 2019] (GitHub)
- Text Summarization Algorithm with GUI. [MAR 2018] (GitHub)
- Web Scraping Project Translator with GUI. [MAR 2018] (GitHub)
- Volumetric Statistical Estimate Preparation Instrumental Analysis (VSEPIA). [MAR 2018] (GitHub)

Honors & Achievements

- Secured 1st prize at Wobot Hackathon for developing end-to-end Lightweight Handwash Detector. (Link 1, Link 2)
- Received **Best Outgoing Student 2019**, from RNS Institute of Technology. (*Link*)
- Received Letter of Appreciation from HoD, ECE, RNSIT for my contribution to the institution. (Link)
- Secured 1st prize in the Software category for "Automatic Helmetless Rider Detection", RNSIT. (Link)
- Secured 2nd prize across all categories for "Automatic Helmetless Rider Detection", RNSIT. (Link)
- Secured **Best Paper Award** at 3rd ICERECT-2018 (*Link*)
- Secured 1st prize in Social Impact category for "VSEPIA" at ECE Open House Expo 2018, RNSIT. (<u>Link</u>)
- Secured 1st prize in Social Impact Category for "Automatic Kitchen Safety Mechanism" at ECE Open House Expo 2017, RNSIT. (Link)